BRIAN GADBOIS

126 Company Farm Road Barre, MA 01005

Phone: 617.515.1717 brian@gadboisfamily.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

IT professional with both entrepreneurial and Fortune 500 experience in providing IT solutions to customers. Significant range of technical experience including program/project management, system architecture design, network implementation, information security, telecommunications systems and business development. Strong ability to translate business needs into technical solutions and communicating complex technical issues to senior executives. Excellent at developing repeatable processes, focusing on details and resolving problems before affecting business objectives.

- 19 years of experience in Information Technology with strong knowledge of network architecture design, implementation, test, and operations and maintenance (O&M)
- 8 years of experience in direct supervisory and matrixed management of technical personnel
- 5 years of experience as project manager of engineering design and implementation of IT projects
- Bachelor's degree in Electrical Engineering, post-graduate courses in Engineering Management
- Training courses in project management, information security and network technologies

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Defense Integration Solutions – *Brockton, Massachusetts Managing Partner/Director of Operations*

12/2009 to 4/2012

Joined as minority partner with a small business start-up company providing wireless network engineering support for the US Navy. As director, provided operational leadership to the company managing operations, finance, contracting, human resources, business development, and purchasing Led team in site surveys, network design, system implementation, and logistics support.

- Grew the company to over \$1.5M in annual revenue in two years building on our relationships with existing customers and expanding our technical reach into new Navy organizations.
- Developed multiple strategic partnerships with large federal government system integrators resulting in long-term contract opportunities with Department of Defense organizations.
- Provided direct project management oversight for the implementation of over 20 networks worldwide providing wireless voice and data connectivity for Navy ships in port.
- Negotiated all company's contracts and teaming agreements with nine different government agencies and prime contractors for engineering services over two years and into the future.

Templar Technology – Charlton, Massachusetts Independent Consultant 9/2005 to 12/2009

Founded IT consulting practice with a focus on the federal government specializing in Project Management, Network Operations, Information Security, and Business Development. Acted as senior advisor for large business system integrators for business development efforts. Led proposal development submissions, provided technical consulting services, led proposal reviews teams, developed complex system architectures and technical design documentation for government organizations.

- Senior Test Engineer for large scale Air Force Network Operations system deployment. Led test team in the development of 200+ system tests to validate system functionality and operational verification. Interfaced with government technical representatives to facilitate test acceptance. Developed system Test Plan for system acceptance.
- Led engineering team in developing detailed design and integration documentation in web based access to enterprise network management system comprised of multiple distinct software packages. Installed and configured system, documented installation configuration, and troubleshooting and maintenance procedures.

BRIAN GADBOIS

110 Partridge Hill Rd Charlton, MA 01507 Phone: 617.515.1717 brian@gadboisfamily.com

Independent Consultant (continued)

- Created comprehensive documentation for worldwide intranet architecture. Documented system functionality capabilities and security mechanisms and created system level architectural diagrams for 20+ subsystem software packages.
- Led team of engineers developing detailed 50+ page responses for four technical proposals over four day period comprising an enterprise level MS Active Directory solution, an enterprise help desk/work flow system, an information security boundary system implementation, and a training solution. Assigned work projects to team members, consolidated inputs, developed cost and schedule estimates, and prepared briefing to customer senior management.

General Dynamics, Network Systems - Needham, Massachusetts Senior Member Technical Staff 7/2000 to 9/2005

Recruited to lead new information security practice for the Army Solutions division. Led the technical design, implementation and testing of network deployments. Provided technical expertise for the company's response to government solicitations. Consistently promoted to higher responsible positions.

- Deputy Program Manager for Engineering. Led engineering group to re-design the Air Force's primary enterprise Information Security, Network Management, and Intranet architectures. Primary interface for government customer. Grew the contract value from \$2M to over \$25M.
- Lead Information Security Engineer. Lead engineer developing the information security design, integration, and testing efforts. Led the system Security Test & Evaluation (ST&E) effort.
- Lead Information Security Engineer, Internal Development projects. Developed developmental strategy for research projects. Researched capability requirements among various business areas.
- Senior member technical proposal team. Developed technical proposals for multiple projects for Federal Government customers including US Navy, US Army, and National Intelligence Agency.
- Lead Project Engineer. Led the design, integration, configuration, and installation of network security solution for three campus networks.

United States Air Force, Active Duty, Communications Officer

4/1993 to 7/2000

EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts – Lowell, Massachusetts Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Program Management, Project Management, WiFi, Wireless LAN, RF engineering, spectrum analysis, circuit emulation, Wireless Intrusion Detection Systems (WIDS), Security Event Management (SEM) systems, Firewalls, VPN gateways, Network and Host Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS), web caching and mail relay appliances, load balancing switches, network and system vulnerability assessment tools, security policy management system, Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) systems, Enterprise management systems, Network Management Systems (NMS), network protocol and security analyzers, system fault management tools, network routers and switches, backup storage devices, web development.